<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE glsa SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/glsa.dtd">
<glsa id="202507-06">
    <title>openh264: Heap Overflow</title>
    <synopsis>A heap overflow has been discovered in openh264, which can lead to arbitrary code execution.</synopsis>
    <product type="ebuild">openh264</product>
    <announced>2025-07-08</announced>
    <revised count="1">2025-07-08</revised>
    <bug>950112</bug>
    <access>remote</access>
    <affected>
        <package name="media-libs/openh264" auto="yes" arch="*">
            <unaffected range="ge">2.6.0</unaffected>
            <vulnerable range="lt">2.6.0</vulnerable>
        </package>
    </affected>
    <background>
        <p>OpenH264 is a codec library which supports H.264 encoding and decoding. It is suitable for use in real time applications such as WebRTC.</p>
    </background>
    <description>
        <p>A vulnerability has been discovered in openh264. Please review the CVE identifiers referenced below for details.</p>
    </description>
    <impact type="high">
        <p>A vulnerability in the decoding functions of OpenH264 codec library could allow a remote, unauthenticated attacker to trigger a heap overflow.

This vulnerability is due to a race condition between a Sequence Parameter Set (SPS) memory allocation and a subsequent non Instantaneous Decoder Refresh (non-IDR) Network Abstraction Layer (NAL) unit memory usage. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by crafting a malicious bitstream and tricking a victim user into processing an arbitrary video containing the malicious bitstream. An exploit could allow the attacker to cause an unexpected crash in the victim&#39;s user decoding client and, possibly, perform arbitrary commands on the victim&#39;s host by abusing the heap overflow.</p>
    </impact>
    <workaround>
        <p>There is no known workaround at this time.</p>
    </workaround>
    <resolution>
        <p>All openh264 users should upgrade to the latest version:</p>
        
        <code>
          # emerge --sync
          # emerge --ask --oneshot --verbose ">=media-libs/openh264-2.6.0"
        </code>
    </resolution>
    <references>
        <uri link="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2025-27091">CVE-2025-27091</uri>
        <uri>GHSA-m99q-5j7x-7m9x</uri>
    </references>
    <metadata tag="requester" timestamp="2025-07-08T22:26:50.251377Z">graaff</metadata>
    <metadata tag="submitter" timestamp="2025-07-08T22:26:50.255190Z">sam</metadata>
</glsa>